# Joao Costa

New York, NY 10009

Phone: 917 306 1291 Email: costa.16@yahoo.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/joao-costa-919535193/

Github: https://github.com/jCosta16

Data analyst who enjoys acquire new knowledge and face new challenges. Fast learner and good problem-solver with great team and leadership abilities. Experienced in working with executive staff and promoting collaboration across different parts of an organization. With knowledge in Agile methodology and Python, MySQL, MongoDB, HTML/CSS/JavaScript, Tableau and Machine Learning skills.

#### Technical Skills

**Tools:** Python, VBA, JavaScript, Mongo, SQL, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, D3, Tableau, Machine Learning

# **Projects**

#### Caixa Habitacao APP

Link: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=br.gov.caixa.habitacao&hl=en US

- APP that offers services for clients with House Loan Contracts.
- Product Owner, User Tester and Requirement approval.
- API (JSON, XLM), SCRUM

#### **NBA Draft Dashboard**

Link: https://jcosta16.github.io/Basketball/

- This application is a deep dive into data concerning NBA drafts, salaries, and colleges.
- HTML/CSS, JavaScript (D3, Leaflet, Plotly), Python, JSON, Google Maps API and SQL

## **Breast Cancer Diagnosis using Machine Learning**

Link: https://github.com/jCosta16/ELT Project

- Cancer Diagnosis using Machine Learning.
- Python, scikit-learn, keras, Matplotlib

#### **Relevant Experience**

# **Product Owner/ Team Member**

2017 - 2018

#### Caixa Economica Federal

Brasília, Brazil

Used critical thinking to manage the backlog for projects, as well as produced Business Requirement Documents and reviewed Functional Requirement Documents for projects. Tested and approved functionalities, with special attention to details. Worked in different projects at same time with great

teamwork capacity. Used leadership and team work skills to promote collaboration across different teams and parts of the organization.

## Key Accomplishments:

- Participated actively in the development of "Caixa Habitação APP" allows more than 3 million potential users to access services for their Housing Loan contracts.
- Developed Housing Loan contracts solutions for Online Banking.
- Awards: 2017 Best Project VP of Housing Loan

## Senior Consultant | Corporate

2016 - 2018

### Caixa Economica Federal

Brasília, Brazil

Used research and analytical skills to produce technical studies on market trend analysis, in order to propose improvement of existing products and services and development of new ones. Coordinated and promoted improvement regarding systems and processes, set up scenarios to develop awareness through SWOT analysis. Provided information and developed solutions regarding products and services of the company supporting decision making.

# **Additional Experience**

# **Regional Operations Supervisor**

2014 - 2016

#### Caixa Economica Federal

Brasília, Brazil

Working with real estate construction financing for companies, supervised the operational work involved in processing real estate financing contracts. With critical thinking identified opportunities and apply product knowledge to offer the right product to customers. Collaborate with different areas of the company, aiming to solve problems and deliver a better customer experience.

#### **Operations Housing Loan Supervisor**

2012 - 2014

#### Caixa Economica Federal

Brasília, Brazil

Oversaw the operational work involved in processing Housing Loan contracts.

### **Housing Loan Analyst**

2011 - 2012

## Caixa Economica Federal

Brasília, Brazil

Operational work involved in processing Housing Loan contracts.

## **Education**

**Bootcamp Certificate: Columbia University**, New York City, NY - A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Python, JavaScript, SQL Databases, Tableau, Big Data, and Machine Learning.

Bachelor's Degree: Accounting and Finance, Universidade de Brasília, Brasília, Brazil.

Graduate Degree: Accounting and Finance, UDF, Brasília, Brazil.